MILAN KACAR

Software & Survey Engineer

@ milankacar@live.com Milan Kacar

4 +43 677 614 375 95 @MilanKacar

Q Graz , Austria in https://at.linkedin.com/in/milan-kacar

% https://milankacar.github.io/CV/ @ @milan_kacar



ABOUT ME

I am a Software Engineer & Survey Engineer with 1.5 year of professional experience. I graduated Geodesy at Graz University of Technology in Austria, where I work as a project and teaching assistant. I am currently enrolled in two Master's degree programs: Geodesy & Computer Science at the same university. I grew up in Mrkonjic Grad (Republic of Srpska, BA) where I finished my highschool having Mathematics, Logic and Physics at higher level.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

■ Date of birth 01.09.1995 Birthplace Banja Luka, BA Citizenship Austrian Marital status Single Sex Male

EDUCATION

GYMNASIUM

2010 - 2014 Mrkonjic Grad, BA

BSc Geomatics Engineering University of Technology, TU Graz

2015 - 2019 Q Graz. Austria

Master's Degree Programme - Geodesy

University of Technology, TU Graz

2019-Present **Q** Graz, Austria

Master's Degree Programme - Computer Science

University of Technology, TU Graz

2020-Present Graz. Austria

UNIVERSITY & PERSONAL PROJECTS

- STOCK PRICES PREDICTOR Project uses AI (Artificial intelligence) and ML (Machine learning) as a hybrid approach to detect prices fluctuation for stocks considering different indexes (SP 500, Dow Jones, DAX etc.)
- LOTTO NUMBERS PREDICTOR It was a try to predict lotto numbers for the next draw.
- SCIENTIFIC PAPER MINER This project is GOOGLE for scientific papers.
- POLLEN TREE DETECTOR (FROM SATELLITE IMAGES) This project presents an automated tree detecting and identification method based on image processing of satellite imagery.
- DIFFERENT SIGNAL PROCESSING PROJECTS Mostly projects on GNSS signals.
- GRAVITY ANOMALY MAPS GRACE misson.
- KALMAN FILTER · ADEVANCED KALMAN FILTER · PARTICLE FILTER as a part of indoor navigation.
- DIFFERENT ARDUINO PROJECTS Mostly projects from youtube tutorials and combination of different projects.

LOOKING FOR

"To work in a progressive and dynamic organization where one could solve scientific enigmas and contribute towards welfare of society "

TECHNICAL STRENGTH

TEGITITO TEGITIETT	
Python	•••••
C/C++	•••••
GIS	•••••
PostgreSQL	•••••
Navigation	•••••
MATLAB	•••••
GNSS	•••••
Signal Processing	•••••
Java	•••••
Data Structures & Algorithms	••••
MySQL	••••
Docker	••••
Kubernetes	••••
PHP	••••
Linux	••••
R	••••
Apache Spark	••••
Skala	••••

Java Script

DISSERTATION WORK

BSc Thesis

Database for cycling routes

- Entity Relationship Diagram.
- Building the Database.
- Conversion from analog to digital maps.

MSc Thesis

PV (Photovoltaic) panels detection from satellite images

- Project uses AI (Artificial intelligence) and ML (Machine learning) as a hybrid approach to detect panels.
- Building an independent model to work on different datasets.
- CapsNets for object detection.
- YOLOv5

WORK EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant

TU Graz

March 2021 - Present

9 Graz, Austria

- Integrated navigation
- Sensor fusion
- Indoor navigation

Software Engineer

TU Graz

Sep 2019 - Present

Graz, Austria

- Automation
- Statistics
- Geoinformatics
- Automotive industry

Survey Engineer

GEODATA

₩ July 2019 - December 2020

Semmering Basistunnel, Austria

- Tunnel surveying
- 3D Laser scanner measurements

HOBBIES



Reading

I am trying to read a book per week.



Sports Addict

At a young age I enjoyed playing tennis, but my interests migrated towards Fitness and healthy food.



Travelling

After living in a rustic, small town for the past 18 years, I was craving change and adventure. Six years later, I've traveled to more places during college than the first two decades of my life.

STRENGTHS

Hard-working Decision Making

Ability to Work Under Pressure

Motivator & Leader

Conflict Resolution

Time Management

Target oriented | Able to travel

Flexibility and Adaptability

Problem solver

LANGUAGES

Serbian | Croatian | Bosnian German **English** Russian

